Rikesh Shah

Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

linkedin.com/in/rikesh-shah-406903151

Contact: +91 98258 05034

Email: rikeshshahshah@gmail.com

Summary

Hi, I am Rikesh Shah.

I've been in the sales field for over 23 years, and have managed the state of Gujarat across various roles.

I am capable of training and appointing new sales officers. My network has allowed me to appoint various SE, SO, TSI, and even ASM, and my experience has helped me train them in the ways of the company.

In budding companies, I have proved myself capable of building the sales infrastructure from the ground up. In stable companies, I have been able to manage and upgrade on the existing sales infra, including product launches and placements, as well as designing sales schemes, and countering competition's moves.

I have also been able to manage my relationships with my dealers and distributors, which have been helpful in better management of the product placement and marketing.

I can help your company at any stage of its sales growth including

- New area
- New customers
- New consumers
- New sales staff.

Thank You.

Experience

Branch Manager

Kores (India) Ltd.

Aug 2017 - Present (5 years 7 months)

Currently handling all of Gujarat. Includes 112 dealer and distributors across all districts, and managing 7 sales officers, and one ASM directly reporting to me.

Work also includes designing product launch strategies and schemes, tracking competition activity and setting up countermeasures, and increasing area coverage.

---- Area Sales Manager

Dr. Reddy's Laboratories

Mar 2015 - Aug 2017 (2 years 6 months)

Handled sales operations of the state of Gujarat. Managed 9 sales officers, reporting directly to me. Designed sales routes. Handled product placement during launches and did other brand extensions as well.



Area Sales Manager

LT Foods LTD (D A A W A T Basmati Rice)

May 2014 - Mar 2015 (11 months)

Handled sales throughout Gujarat, i.e. Primary and Secondary Sales. Took care of 8 super stockists and 25 sub stockists. Managed 6 sales officers on company payroll, and paved way for sales infrastructure for new product launches in the state.

⊯ Area Sales Manager

MAKSON GROUP

Nov 2013 - May 2014 (7 months)

Built sales infrastructure in the state of Gujarat from the start. Appointed new sales executives and representatives. Appointed super stockist and distributors.



🔓 Regional Growth Manager

Parle Agro Pvt Ltd

Aug 2012 - Nov 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Covering entire Central Gujarat, managing 19 growth officers on company payroll with direct reporting to me. Designed dispatch plans for distributors far from the depot. Focused on brand-wise achievements.

Area Sales Manager

Piramal Group

Jul 2009 - Jul 2012 (3 years 1 month)

Handled all OTC product sales for South Gujarat, covering 28 distributors across the territory, and handling 16 field force with directly answerable to me, delivering 60% growth year on year.

Territory Sales Incharge

Unilever

Jun 2004 - Jul 2009 (5 years 2 months)

Handled all FMCG Sales products of Hindustan Unilever, including food and beverages, and home and personal care.

Education



🎮 Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda, Vadodara

Postgraduate Degree, Chemistry

1977 - 1999

Post graduate degree in Industrial Chemistry.

🎮 Maharaja Sayajirao University of Baroda, Vadodara

Bachelor of Science, Chemistry

1994 - 1997

Majored in Chemistry

Skills

Marketing Management • Product Launch • Sales Schemes • Direct Sales • Product Placement • Sales Routes • Distributor Management • Sales Management • Dealer Management • Personnel Selection

Other details:

DOB: 10 September, 1975 Current CTC: ₹12 LPA

Permanent address: A 103, Kishan Platina, Opposite DevPushp Hospitals, Harshad Nagar

Society, Tulsidham Square, Manjalpur, Vadodara - 390011

Temporary address: G-18, Shikhar Apartments, near GVBaa school, Ghodasar, Ahmedabad